[SPEAKER_00] Okay, so we're going to start off this class with everyone's name, right? Because before, you know, we weren't sure who was going to stay, but now all of you are here to stay, right, inshallah? So the end of the course, right, not until two or three weeks when you start having other commitments and you get bored, or you get tired of memorizing, or anything like that, right? We're going to stay until the end of the course, right, inshallah? Inshallah. So I want to get everybody's name down, not just for me, right? Many of you, I'm glad, know your names already, but I want everybody to pay attention, right? Usually when a teacher asks for names, you're just like, all right, that's for the teacher to know, but I want everybody to know each other's names, right? Technically, we should be knowing each other's names anyways, because as Muslims, we are brothers. And especially as constituents of the same masjid, we all come to
[SPEAKER_00] the same masjid. Most of you, or all of you, inshallah, are always here. So we should know each other's names, and we should know each other, and we should also keep an eye on each other. The sahaba, radiallahu anhum, we would see that they would actually always be wondering, oh, where is such and such person? He didn't come to the masjid today. Whereas, unfortunately, our situation is such that, you know, a person could be gone for the masjid. He comes to the masjid every day, but he's gone for months, and nobody even asks about him, right? So the state of a believer is such that he should always be aware of his brothers. We should know each other's names. We should say salam to each other, right? We shouldn't just stick to our own cliques and groups. Rather, we should meet all the brothers, because our connection is only for the sake of Allah, not for any other reason. We shouldn't only meet those brothers we know for some other reason, or have a connection to for some other reason. And plus, I'm going to test you guys, at least on the name of those who are next to you, inshallah, when we get to that point in the lesson. Which will come later today, inshallah. So when I ask you, who is this,
[SPEAKER_00] then you better know their name, right? So just pay attention, inshallah. So we'll start from the right. Right here. As-salamu alaykum. My name is Zeeshan. Ameen. My name is Mustafa. Mustafa. As-salamu alaykum. My name is Hussain. Hussain. As-salamu alaykum. My name is Hamad. Hamad. Hamad. As-salamu alaykum. My name is Hamim. Hamim. As-salamu alaykum. My name is Abdullazim. As-salamu alaykum. Abdullazim. As-salamu alaykum. As-salamu alaykum. My name is Yusuf. Yusuf. As-salamu alaykum. My name is Shanawise. As-salamu alaykum. My name is Uzair. Mr. Musumeer. As-salamu alaykum. As-salamu alaykum. financial assistance. Just say your name very loudly and quickly. My name is Hussein. My name is Hussein. Hussein. My name is Ibrahim. Ibrahim. My name is Dawood. Dawood. My name is Samir. Semir. Jibril, Wali, Zubair,
[SPEAKER_00] Musharraf, Ayaan, Mukhtar, Tamir, Salim, Yahya, Basel. So at least remember, I know it's going to be possible to remember everything, but at least remember the brothers that are next to you. I'm going to ask you about the brothers that are next to you, inshallah. Ali. Shayan. Bilal. Bilal. Adel. Adel. Munira. Munira. Abdullah. Ilyas. Ilyas. Haq. Haq. Shiraz. Shiraz. Salim. Salim. Khayam. Khayam. Abdul Raqib. Abdul Raqib. Yasir. Yasir. Umar. Fariz. Fariz. Umar. Umar. Umar. Mustafa. Mustafa. Mustafa. Osman. Osman. Samir. Samir. Umar. Umar. Zayn. Zayn. Qash. Umar. Amin. Amin.
[SPEAKER_00] Saqib. Saqib. Saqib. Atherid. Umar. Umar. Oh, you're getting a book? I'm sorry. I'm sorry. There's no more. Oh, we're finished? What's up? Can you just ask everyone to raise your hand one more time so we know who doesn't have a book? Yeah. Whoever does not have a book yet, please raise your hand. I'm sure. Okay, Salim, Abbasu, and the brother in the top. Thank you.
[SPEAKER_00] So the last lesson, we learned a few things. We didn't go into too many details because a significant portion was discussing the etiquettes of seeking knowledge, and that's definitely a very important aspect. Can somebody remind me of one etiquette of seeking knowledge? We should respect our books and the tools we use for learning. Very good, mashallah. Respect our books and the tools we use for learning. Very good, mashallah. Khalid Jibril? We should make sure that our intentions are for the sake of Allah. Very good. Make sure our intentions are purely and solely for the sake of Allah, not for anything else. Anybody remember the meaning of the hadith that I mentioned in this regard? The warning that we mentioned. That was the orientation. With regards to our intention. Is it that? Is it this one? No, before that. Basically, it was a hadith. It said that whoever seeks knowledge for the purpose of competing with the scholars,
[SPEAKER_00] so that he can argue with foolish people, or so that he can turn people's attention towards him, then Allah will enter him into the fire and elevate all of us. So let's all renew our intention and make sure that none of these are our intention. And normally, unfortunately, whenever somebody does have a bad intention, these are the three main reasons. Either they want to be considered as being with the scholars, and competing with them, or they want to argue with people just for the sake of debating and things like that. Or they want to turn people's attention towards them and they want the fame and the name. So we have to take all these intentions out of our hearts and make our intention purely for the Allah. Very good. Any other intentions, etiquettes that we mentioned for seeking knowledge? The book in an elevated place. Good, yeah. That's one etiquette that scholars mention that one part of it is to keep a book in an elevated place. In the malama, the baniya. In the malama, the baniya. Actually, it's only based on intention. Very good. Humble ourselves. Humble ourselves. Very good.
[SPEAKER_00] MashaAllah. Oh, you said, you had mentioned scholar, that the etiquette is that it can be to such an extent that the person can shift themselves with the book, like a scholar in the past had mentioned. Yeah, very good. So we mentioned that one scholar had so much etiquette for his books that he would actually shift himself rather than moving the book. Respecting classmates. Respecting classmates. Good, mashaAllah. You're missing one more. Respecting? The lesson. The lesson, good. And? The teacher. Teacher. I'm sorry. Okay, I think we're missing one more thing, but inshaAllah, you guys can review this. All right. It's being recorded, right? Yeah, it's being recorded here. Hopefully, you can hear the sound is playing properly. InshaAllah, if somebody had a better solution, maybe to connect something to the phone, we can figure it out after, inshaAllah. Okay, so. So, then, now we came to the actual course, we started with the lesson, had a blank, had a
[SPEAKER_00] blank, and we went through all of the vocabulary, so now let's test people, all right? My drawing is not great, right? It's like first grade level, so bear with me, inshaAllah. Let's see. Okay. Okay. Say it again. Yeah, except it's with the and the . Very good, inshaAllah. Okay. Okay. Okay. It's very funny looking, but, sorry, remind me of your name again? Ayana. Ayana, okay. .
[SPEAKER_00] Very good, inshaAllah. . Yes, . . Very good, inshaAllah. . Very good, inshaAllah. . . All right. My question is, how do you focus on worship Yeah, of course, I do, now that everything's. this is a very bad drawing
[SPEAKER_00] let's see very good just a reminder that say all the vowels so say the reason as we mentioned in the last lesson is so that we get used to pronouncing the end vowels because that's actually very important when we're learning the Arabic language knowing what the end of the letter is, right? Later on once we each other master the Arabic language and we're just having a conversation then you don't necessarily have to pronounce every single vowel at the end of the words but while we're learning it is very important for us to do so so that we can make sure we have the correct pronunciations okay um um um let's see yeah Ali, what is this?
[SPEAKER_00] is it because of my drawing you can't recognize what it is or? oh okay do you want to lift it up? what is this? ahsan means you did good like whenever somebody does something good like if a teacher normally in their lessons they'll say good job right so ahsanta it's a verb we'll learn the detail of that later but it means that you did a good job you did something which is good ahsanta ahsanta ahsanta ahsanta ahsanta ahsanta ahsanta ahsanta ahsanta ahsanta ahsanta ahsanta ahsanta so uh ahsanta good in the
[SPEAKER_00] direction of our models ok now we're gonna our F deeply dong Um What is this? What is this? Wait Alright Alright, we can move on Um Um Um Yes, oh you're sitting was here Um Yeah Is this a mosque? No No, this is a mosque Alright Um Is this a key? No, this is a pen Alright Pen Alright Um What is this? Is this a star? No, this is a star Alright Um
[SPEAKER_00] Um Sorry, can you repeat the name again? Um Um Um Um Um Um Um Um Um Um Um Um Hmm Hmm Um Well done
[SPEAKER_00] Alright inshallah So we all get the picture We understand the concept Alhamdulillah And somebody remind me What are the three things Well we'll ask each person one thing Right And somebody I didn't call on yet The three things that hadha indicates The word hadha What are the three things that it indicates Somebody I didn't call on yet Qasha Just
[SPEAKER_00] tell me one thing It's something that's close Okay very good Very good Something close rather than far Alright Second thing Something singular Something singular Very good So if it's two or more Then you don't use the word hadha And brother Bilal Something male Something male Very good These are the three things that the word hadha Is used for Right If any of these three change Then the word used for changes Now what's the word used That's something That we're going to find out Inshallah What was the last one Male Yeah Male Masculine Yeah masculine Yeah masculine We also mentioned last time That in the Arabic language Every noun Is either male or female That's unlike the English language For things we don't use You know we don't have genders For things right Like books For example We don't say this book is male or female It's just a thing Right Male or female We only use for animals Or human beings But in the Arabic language Everything is either
[SPEAKER_00] Masculine Or feminine Right There's no What do you call it Third option There's no gender fluidity As you mentioned Right So So that's another thing Then one more thing we learned is A couple of families We were introduced to a couple of families Right Can anybody name one of the families We were introduced to Ism al-Mishallah Ism al-Mishallah Right Ism al-Mishallah I'll maybe write that on the board So you know how it looks Sorry I didn't really use the The Board last time Actually let me not use The shortcuts Okay Ism al-Mishallah I'm going to write that Okay Ism al-Mishallah Ism al-Mishallah Alright Ism al-Mishallah That's the singular version If you want to write the plural The name like the fact
[SPEAKER_00] that it's a word You would write Asmaa Asmaa is a plural Which means Those words that are used for So what is Ism al-Mishallah That's the Arabic term What is it used for What does this family like to do What are they known for doing They point towards people Right They're very judgmental Right So they They all like to point fingers at other people Right I'm just It's obviously a joke But it's a way to Under To remember What the Go The job of these words are Right So which of the words that we learned so far Falls under this category Of Ism al-Mishallah Or Asmaa al-Mishallah Yes What's the word The word Think That Oh Hada Hada Hada Hada is In this category So what I want you guys to do is Have a section In your notebook For all these categories These families That we're going to be introduced to Right So We already learned This one family is Asmaa al-Mishallah Right Those That Judgmental family That likes to Point At
[SPEAKER_00] fingers At other people Right Meaning This is the group of words that are used To indicate towards things To point at things Right So Hada is the first one We're going to learn We learn And Next We're going to learn another one In the next lesson Which we hopefully will get to Today Inshallah Right So Hada And we already know the three qualities Or three things that Hada indicates towards Right Everybody got that Yeah No Ism is not feminine This is feminine Yeah We'll get to all that Inshallah The difference between male And masculine And feminine Etc Right There was one more thing Yeah Hada Right So What did we learn What is Ah Right What is Does it have any meaning by itself No Not necessarily Right It's Question mark Yeah You could say it's like a question mark Yeah So Ah Is used to turn Whatever
[SPEAKER_00] Sentence You have Into a question Right So Hada is just a statement This is a house But As soon as you add Ah It's like Like your brother mentioned It's like a question mark Right So it turns that same statement Into a question So now you're asking Is this a house Is this a house Everybody understand So Which family was that part of The last one Yeah Very good So I made a It's Just to be more accurate That's good That's what I said last time But just to be a little bit more accurate I want to Ah Ah Modify the name a little bit It's Ah That's the The family That Is This is Part of Um Part of The family Of Which family Is this Hav I Is Hav It's Hav It's Hav Hav It's Hav It's
[SPEAKER_00] Hav Hav Hav Hav Hav want to know more and more about things, right? They're very nosy, let's put it like that. This is a nosy family, right? So they're always asking questions. So , let me just put the , right? means tools, right? So these are tools by which we ask questions, okay? So , this is a nosy family. That's the family of things that we use as questions, right? So we learned two of these. We were introduced to two members of this family last time, right? Anybody remember one we already just mentioned, which is , right? The , what's the second one? Yeah, that's the same thing. Yeah, that's one. And the second one? , very good, right? So , it's not under this family. So now this is the second family you can put on a separate page or a separate, just a separate area.
[SPEAKER_00] Right? That's another family. As we learn these different things that are part of the same family, you can put it in that same category. So you have a list, okay, this is part of that family, right? So now we have , then we have , right? Now we said something about , specifically, right? The reason I'm going over it in a little bit more detail is because I felt that we went a little bit too fast last time because I wanted to finish the lesson in time. And we had started late because of different reasons. But inshallah, we'll try to keep a pace where we can keep up because some brothers did mention that we're going a little bit too fast because it was a little bit new to them. So we'll slow down just a little bit, but you still want to get a decent amount done in each lesson. So now, , what things does indicate towards, brother Usaid? Or like, what did we learn about math? Like, what do you use it to ask about? Yeah, but yesterday we learned specifically about questioning. So, sorry? .
[SPEAKER_00] .
[SPEAKER_00] , nobody? You have to pay attention, right? Pay attention, try to implement. So, as soon as that comes, you should be like, oh, I know that word, and it should stick in your mind, right? That's one problem I see is that people don't implement, they learn, they'll learn Arabic, but then they won't implement it, and then that's why they won't really get the hang of how the language works. They'll know all the theoretical rules, but they won't be able to apply it. So, I want to start applying it right away. So, what I said was, . . . . . . . . . . . . . So, you say you learn Arabic, you don't get caught up, they're not cheating, we learn Arabic. Okay. So, essentially, when we learn Arabic, there's a way for us to engage. Because we don't use our mind to analyze Tonkin, there's a lot of people new Here . Allah subhanahu wa ta'ala is telling Adam alayhi salam هذا عدو لك ولي زوجك لك means
[SPEAKER_00] for you and for your wife So look, you already know هذا indicates towards what? Shaytan is a male Shaytan was close by And singular So look, we're already applying what we learned Even though it's just the first lesson It seems very basic But there's a lot of things that we can get from it Similarly, one interesting tidbit For ما ما we learned is only used for things That are That have no intellect Yes, very good That have no intellect But now we see in surah shu'ara Musa alayhi salam is having a dialogue with Fir'aun And he's telling him He's giving him da'wah He's calling towards Allah subhanahu wa ta'ala So what does Fir'aun respond? He says قَالَ فَمَا I can't remember the exact word But he used the word ما for Allah subhanahu wa ta'ala So then the
[SPEAKER_00] question comes up How could he use the word ما for Allah? The answer is that he was actually being condescending As if he was indicating that Your Lord is a thing that has no intellect That's what some ulama mentioned So now, again, just by this one fact that we know already Which is ما We learn that What method Fir'aun was using In his conversation with Musa alayhi salam So there's so much If we just start thinking and asking Obviously don't start thinking and thinking You're a big mufassir And going and giving lectures And saying look هذا and this and ما You just started But at least think And then if you're wondering Okay, but why was ما used here? If he's talking about Allah subhanahu wa ta'ala Then you just ask the teacher And I will tell you that That's actually because of this reason So yeah How would Surah Kafirun Yeah, similar That's a different discussion That's a little bit confusing But that's a very good question Well
[SPEAKER_00] actually, we'll discuss that later on Good question So Surah Kafirun, the word ما لا أعبد ما تعبدون I do not worship what you worship That's indicating to the idols That makes sense But then later on he says ما أعبد What I worship So we'll talk about that That was the question He said ما أعبد ما تعبدون Yeah Okay Now we finished this lesson I think we all got that Everybody got They understand everything in this lesson? No They get the concept now? Yeah Okay فهمتم هل فهمتم Means did you understand Right? For plural Again, don't worry about the terms I'm just going to say these words commonly So it becomes part of your vocabulary Then later on you understand Why it's like Like this in this particular format هل فهمتم Means did you understand Right? So when I say هل فهمتم Then you either say نعم Or لا If you don't understand Then I'll
[SPEAKER_00] repeat it again إن شاء الله هل فهمتم نعم Okay Alright Now let's continue من سيقرأ Who will read? Okay, very loud Which one will read? Page 9 Right there Yeah, very loud If you don't read loud enough Then you're fired And you're going to have to get somebody else Let him read He can figure it out Yeah, mashallah He's a hafidh, mashallah من هذا هذا ولد من هذا هذا طالب من هذا هذا ولد لا هذا وجود ما هذا هذا مسجد من
[SPEAKER_00] هذا هذا تاجر هذا تاجر هذا قلب Yeah, sorry So some of the letters It might not have فتاكة صراطمة After a while It becomes a second nature You won't even need The حركات Like if it's زبرزير بش Right Well, in Arabic We call it فتح كسر الضم If you're not familiar With that terminology Who's not familiar With that terminology? فتح كسر الضم Okay, so let me just write that down Because I'm not going to It's going to be hard for me To say زبرزير بش While I'm like Like teaching Arabic So I'm just going to I'm hoping that everybody Just acclimatize With the Arabic terms Right So this The top one Is called زبر In Urdu But in Arabic it's called فتحة Now If you're familiar with Using theultan
[SPEAKER_00] زبرازم What it means is If you're applying Z Then you use This means And we'll do it's called what? Ziyad. Ziyad, right? But in Arabic it's called? Qasasamah. Whoever already knows this stuff and thinks it's baby stuff, it's easy, don't feel like that, right? We're going to get into the stuff, so everybody should keep in mind that not everybody has the background that you do. So we're trying to keep everybody on the same boat, inshallah. So if we're saying things that you feel are easy, it doesn't mean everybody else feels that it's easy. So just be patient, inshallah. We'll get to a point where you will be now the one, like, you know, okay, what's going on, right? So don't
[SPEAKER_00] worry, inshallah. This is Fesh, right? In Arabic it's called? Qasasamah. So ideally, like, before doing this course, we should have had, like, you know, everybody should have learned Tajweed very properly. Because it's actually important to learn Arabic, to know the proper pronunciation of letters. Because a lot of times you won't even be able to differentiate between three letters. Like, for example, in Urdu, you have Zal, Zod, and Zal, right? These three letters. Right? They all pretty much sound almost the same, right? Whereas in Arabic they sound very different. So now, when we're speaking, then you're writing that down. Let's say I say a word, and then you write it down. If you don't know Tajweed properly, you won't know
[SPEAKER_00] how to differentiate between these three letters, right? So for those who didn't learn Tajweed, try to work on it, or at least the pronunciation of the letters, inshallah. And that will help a lot with this class. Just learning Arabic in general, Tajweed is actually important. It should be, like, a prerequisite in a way. But we wanted to keep this class. It's a little bit more accessible for everybody. But we should all try to work on Tajweed on our own. Besides Tajweed, like, learning to write again. Many of you may not have experience writing, but it's okay. We'll just go as it is, inshallah. It's not so important. We can still learn, and we'll learn how to write along the way, inshallah. Yeah, how do you pronounce that again? Zammah? Bommah. Bommah. Bommah. Bommah. Bommah. Bommah. Bommah. Bommah. Bommah. Bommah. Bommah. Okay. You finished reading or no? Oh, sorry. The point, the reason I mentioned all this is that, yeah, Tajweed. So, it's a kasra on the bottom of the jeen. Tajweed. Kasra meaning zeb. Okay?
[SPEAKER_00] All right. Continue reading. Okay. All right. Hada kalbun. Hada kalbun. La. Hada fittun. Hada hamilun. All right. Jamil? No. It's. The kasra is first. H. Oh. Himarun. Mm-hmm. Ahada himarun. La. Hada hisamun. Hisamun. Mm-hmm. Wama hada. Hada jamalun. Mm-hmm. Ma hada. Hada deekun. Mm-hmm. Man hada. Hada mudawasun. Mudawasun. Oh. Okay. That's another thing that. So, many of us or maybe most of us. We'll be familiar with the, it's what's called the Indo-Pak script of the Quran, right? So, like, if you look at all these Mus'hafs here and over there, most of them are Indo-Pak and you'll have some that are the Arab style, right? The Uthman, Taha, calligraphy font, right? So, many of
[SPEAKER_00] us, when you pick up the other one, we're like, oh, I don't even know how to read this, right? It's like a different language, right? Has anybody had that experience? Yes. Mm-hmm. Right? It's difficult to read? Mm-hmm. So, this book is on that font, right? That's something to note. Now, should, does that mean, oh, that's, this course is not on that? It's not for me, now I can't do it anymore? No. It's not too difficult. Honestly, if you just give it a little bit of time, you'll get used to. There's certain things you need to learn, though. So, one thing I'll teach you right now is that, over here, right? So, let me erase it, here. You know, it's such amazing artwork, but I have to erase it now. Okay. All right. So, we've done, we've done. So, normally, in the Urdu, or like the Indo-Pak font, we would have the zehr, the kasra, on the bottom, right? So, generally, the zehr and the kasra is on the bottom of the word, right? But,
[SPEAKER_00] in this Arabic font, whenever there's a shadda, you guys know what this is, right? Tashdeed or shadda. Everybody knows that, right? Because everybody here should know how to read. So, whenever there's a shadda, then. Whenever, if there's a, if there's a bommah, or, sorry, if there is a fatha, it'll be on top of it. And, if there's a kasra or zehr, then it'll be on the bottom of it. Do you get it? So, it won't be, it won't be down here in the Arabic script. It'll be up here, but this indicates, if it's under the tashdeed, it'll be a zehr or a kasra. And, if it's over, then it'll be a fatha. Get it? Okay. Okay. Okay. Okay. Okay. Yeah, don't know, it'll also be on top. Yeah. Yeah, if it's a shadda. If it's a shadda. Yeah. But, yeah. So, so, yeah. So, if you know, if you look at, again, it's, it's a little bit small, the font here. But, if you look at the font, you
[SPEAKER_00] see the, the, the line is, is it above the tashdeed or shadda, or is it below? Below. Below, right? So, that means it's mudal bison. Mudal bison. If the line was above the shadda, then it would be mudal rasim. Mudal rasim. Everybody get that? So. So, that's, so, that's a trick. So, maybe you can try to pick up the other Qur'an now. Maybe you might be able to read it a little better. Inshallah. So, yeah. So, we have to get used to that script. Because, especially when we start reading Arabic, other Arabic books after we get to a higher level, inshallah, then they're all going to be in that script. So, you have to get used to it. It's a little unrelated to the class, but why was two different scripts made? I mean, the Arabic script was the one that was used mostly. But, it's, it's more, it was more to just facilitate ease of reading. Reading for people from the Indian subcontinent, that they came up with that script. But, yeah. Okay. Um. All right. Kudayin? Ha-da-mi-dee-sun. Ha-ha-da-pa-mi-sun. La-ha-da
[SPEAKER_00] -mi-dee-dun. Okay. All right. We finished the lesson, right? Now, um, what's the main thing? The new, most of this seems pretty repetitive, except there's a lot of new vocabulary. Right? But, what's one new thing? Right? What's one new thing we learned? A new rule, or a new word that we're learning besides the, just the regular, the, the vocabulary? Man. Man. Okay. So, man is part of the nosy family. Right? What's the nosy family? There's one that asks questions a lot. Adawat al-istifham. Right? So, man is part of that nosy family. It's for asking a question. But, it's different than its two counterparts. Right? Remind us again, what's Hamzat al-istifham? What is it? What is it for? It's for a person that happens to look. That happens to look. No, that's the other one. That's ma. Yeah, it's just a question mark. It just adds, it just turns any sentence into a question. Statement into a question. Now, what is ma for?
[SPEAKER_00] Very good, Mashallah. It's for when you're asking about something that has no intellect. That's why it would be translated to what. Right? And then, man. That's the third one. Right? Right? This is? This is similar to ma, except it's for asking about things that have intellect. Right? So, it's for asking. It just means who. Right? In plain English, it means who. But, specifically, it's for asking about things that have intellect. Right? So, if you're asking about a person, then you would use ma. Right? Now, I'm going to start quizzing you guys on each other's names. Ya Shiraz, man hada? Hada khat. Ahsanta. Mashallah. Mashallah. Ya Dawood, man hada? Hada khat. Ahsanta. Mashallah. Ya Zuhayl, man hada? Hada mukhtar. She
[SPEAKER_00] did a little bit of that. Ya Bilal, man hada? Brother Ali. Ahsanta. Ya Usaid, man hada? Hada khat. Hada. Hada. Hada. Hada. Beside tangente. Ye-Shayan, man hada? Dre hammer. Close. Atif. Atatif. Tビه. T V space. Okay. The need means a student, so it's true, technically. Jibreel, is this Jibreel? This is Jibreel, yes. You can tell them your name. Oh, his name? Your name. Oh, my name?
[SPEAKER_00] Iqbal. Excellent, yes, Iqbal. Ya Abdullah, who is this? This is my son. Excellent, mashallah. Okay, so we get the idea, right? When you're using it to ask about somebody, right? So hopefully you remember our neighbor's names. Ya Salim, man hada? Right, excellent. Ya Abdullah Raqim, man hada? Hada Saqib. Hada Saqib. Okay, excellent. Okay, so we all got the idea, right? So it's pretty simple. There's not much. We learned in this lesson. The main thing is man. Everything else is just to kind of solidify what we already learned, right? Except now, there's a lot of new vocabulary in this lesson, which you will have to memorize, right? So tabib is what? If you don't understand the pictures, then I'll explain to you. What is that first picture, hada tabibun?
[SPEAKER_00] What is it? A doctor, right? Tabibun is a doctor. I have to go. Okay, you can go. I'm fine. Tabibun is a doctor, right? The next one, waladun, means a child, right? That might be kind of hard to distinguish what that is, right? Waladun is a child, okay? So just know that. If you can't tell them right now. Tadimun, right? What is a tadib? A student, right? And two students is tadiban. All right. Just putting that out there. Then, rajun, right? What is a rajun? Man. Man, okay. Then, masjid, everybody knows. Tajirun. Merchant, businessman, right? Somebody who's into business, right? Buying and selling. Then, kalbun. If you've heard this, if an Arab brother has called you this, then I feel bad for you.
[SPEAKER_00] Dog, right? Kalb is dog, right? This comes in the Quran, too. Any Hufad, where does it come in the Quran? Quick, quick, quick. We don't have time. Tell me the ayah, tell me the ayah. Come on, come on, come on. Three. It's fine. وَكَلْبُهُمْ بَاسِطٌ ذِرَعَيْهِ بِالْوَصِيبِ It's talking about the dog, but with the people of the cave. All right, good, mashallah. All right. هَذَا كَذُنْ لَعَنَا ذَا قِطٌ What is a qit? Cat. It sounds like cat, too, right? It's possible that there's some relationship in the etymology, right? Qit is a cat, right? هَذَا حِمَارٌ That's going to be a lot of brothers. That's his favorite word, right? حِمَار is a donkey, right? So don't call each other donkeys, right? هَذَا حِمَار Okay. هَذَا حِمَار هَذَا حِصَان حِصَان is a? Horse. Horse, okay. هَذَا جَمَل Okay, the head is خَرَفْ So you can already tell this is a? Camel. Camel, right? Where does جَمَل come in the Qur'an?
[SPEAKER_00] حُفَال قُلْصَمَط Quick, quick, quick, five seconds. زِشَان Come on, come on. We'll say it. شَيَان مُصْصَفَة We're saying come on, quick. Five seconds. Come on, come on, come on, quickly. Where does جَمَل come in the Qur'an? Come on, come on. You guys failed, man. حَتَّى مُؤْمِن حَتَّى يَلِجَ الْجَمَلُ بِسَمِّ الْحِيَاةِ Allah is saying that the people who reject His ayat and they are arrogant from them, they will never enter Jannah until a camel goes into the hole of a needle. The hole of a needle is how small? Very small, right? When will a camel ever go into a hole of a needle? Never, right? So Allah is saying that it's a form of exaggeration just to make a point that they will never enter Jannah, right? So that's where the word جَمَل comes in the Qur'an. So Hufad, you
[SPEAKER_00] better start remembering, right? حَمَلًا حَمَلًا حَمَلًا حَمَلًا حَمَلًا حَمَلًا حَمَلًا حَمَلًا حَمَلًا حَمَلًا That's a very good question but that's outside the scope of our class right now. So when we get to a higher level we'll discuss those things. Very good question though, mashaAllah. I like the way you're thinking. Keep that mindset. Very good, mashaAllah. دِيكٌ is a rooster, right? Not just any chicken, right? Because a chicken, a hen is like دَجَاجَةٌ but دِيك specifically is a rooster. What's the difference between a hen and a rooster? مَيَوْتِنَا مَيَوْتِنَا, right? Okay, good. مُدَرِّيسٌ مُدَرِّيسٌ مُدَرِّيسٌ مُدَرِّيسٌ is a teacher, okay? So هَذَا مُدَرِّيسٌ مُدَرِّيس is a teacher. It comes from the same word as دَرْس. دَرْس means lesson, right? So you get the understanding again how that is the case, how it takes its form. That's what we'll learn as it goes on, inshaAllah. But you should keep this in mind that these root letters have a general meaning and it applies
[SPEAKER_00] to all the words that include it, right? So دَرْس means to study. So مُدَرِّيس is a person. It's a person who teaches, right? So there's a connection there. So just keep that in mind. You'll learn how that connection is made later on, inshaAllah. Then هَذَا طَمِيسٌ, right? طَمِيس is, we learned last time, shirt, right? لَا هَذَا مِنْدِي If you can't tell, that is a very random shape thing. It's just a handkerchief, right? And مِنْدِي is a cloth or a handkerchief. Cloth specifically, the ones that's used for like, you know, people don't really use handkerchiefs over here. But a handkerchief is, for those who don't know, for young guys, for Gen Z, a handkerchief is something that people back in the day used to keep in their pocket. And they used to take it out, and they used to, you know, clean themselves. Okay, so that's our vocabulary for today. So everybody learned that vocabulary. Now, the class time is up, sorry. Yes, 9.19, so we'll end the class now. I
[SPEAKER_00] want to do the next lesson too, but I guess we'll start next time, inshaAllah. Now, your homework is also, again, to read the Tumreen. Where is it? Where is it? Okay. Tumreen. فِي الطلق وقته مَا هذَا هَذَا طَلَمَنَا So it's pretty simple Tumreen. All you have to do is rewrite it, right? But it's good to rewrite it because you'll, um, you'll, it'll help you practice writing, right? So there's no, you don't have to use your brain for this. You just have to, kind of, read it, and write it down. But also try to understand it. Read it, understand it. Actually, let me add something to it. Translate it, right? Write the translation under it, right? So your homework is to write this down and translate it. Everybody got that? Yes. So the Tumreen here, again, we mentioned Tumreen means what? Exercise. Tumreen means exercise, right? So, 11, just, just this one on page 11 on the bottom. On page 11 on the bottom you see it, right? Just that. Just write it down. Memorize the vocabulary. And, okay, we'll do that tomorrow, inshallah. Next, I mean, next session, inshallah. This one, says,
[SPEAKER_00] But children say, مَنْ هَذَا وَلَدُونَ لَهَذَا رَدُونُونَ Because this is a person with intellect. Yeah, very good question. Yeah, very good. It's a good question. So, there's a difference, when you're saying مَنْ هَذَا it means you don't have any idea of who it is. You're just saying, who is this? When you're saying, أَهَذَا وَلَدُونَ like you're, you're suggesting that is this such and such. You get what I'm saying? So that's why you're using that, the word هَمْزَا You get it? But when you're asking about something, اِفْتِدَاءَ meaning you have no idea what it is. Right. You're saying مَنْ هَذَا Who is this? Right. But if you have like some doubt about something, but you just want to confirm if that's the case or not, and you say, for example, أَهَذَا بَابٌ It looks like a bab to me. Then you say, نَعْمْ هَذَا بَابٌ Right. Or if it's a building, you say, أَهَذَا مَسْجِرٌ لا، هَذَا بَيْتٌ Right. So, you use that when you have, you're not 100% sure about something. Right. But if you have no idea what it is, you say مَنْ هَذَا or مَنْ هَذَا
[SPEAKER_00] Yeah, we'll do that other homework ahead of mine. But InshaAllah, I'm going to start giving you guys homework from the Qur'an as well. Like, you know, for example, find five places... Actually, let's just do that. Find five places that have هَذَا in it. Right. And look at a translation. And look at a translation of a Qur'an and see, and try to think why is it that هَذَا is used there. Because sometimes, هَذَا, as we mentioned one example already, sometimes the words are used not necessarily in their normal grammatical usage, but there's a wisdom behind it, right? Like I told you about Fir'aun, why did he use مَ It's because he was trying to, now we'll look at that, insult the God of Musa . Right. So, many times in the Qur'an, you'll see that, you'll be like, wait, we learned that هَذَا is for this, this, this. So why is it being used for this? Right. So I'll bring up a question of mine and we can discuss that in the class, InshaAllah. Right. So that's part of the homework too. Come up with five examples of هَذَا. If you want to cheat, you can cheat. You can, you know, Google, Google
[SPEAKER_00] it. Yeah, find five places, where is it in Qur'an? Yeah, yeah. That's all. You can Google if you want, if you find it difficult, right? Because it could, honestly for a profile, it's much easier. So if you find it difficult, you can Google it. It should be quran.com, right? It's a place where you can, but you would have to learn how to type Arabic, so it's difficult. Okay, this is optional homework, right? For whoever wants to do it, they can do it, InshaAllah. Because I can recognize that it can be difficult, for brothers, especially who are not profiled. Like you just go through page and page in front of like, where is the هَذَا, so. There's an app called تَرْتِيه where you can read it into it. So if you say هَذَا to it, it will search up. Really? Okay. So the brother said there's an app called تَرْتِيه. Google translated that too. Oh, Google translated that too. I have a question. So just a suggestion maybe. If you, what if you ask us to do it, but for those who do it from the Qur'an, you can show it up front to you? But meaning what? Rather than just
[SPEAKER_00] doing, we should translate, but will we actually show you in the Qur'an? Yeah, that's fine. We can come and show you. Sure. From the classes. Yeah, no problem, InshaAllah. Alright, we can end here, InshaAllah. SubhanAllah, we come to this. SubhanakAllah, wa bi-Kurdi, bi-Kashar, wa-Llahi, bi-Maliki, bi-Maliki, bi-Maliki, bi-Maliki, bi-Maliki, bi-Maliki, bi-Maliki, bi-Maliki, bi-Maliki, bi-Maliki, bi-Maliki, bi-Maliki, bi-Maliki, bi-Maliki, bi-Maliki, bi-Maliki, bi-Maliki.